<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>daily reflections</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/</link>
<description>alcoholics anonymous daily reflections</description>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 240522</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240522.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240522.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>STEP ONE</p></h1>
<p><em>WE . . . (The first word of the First Step)</em></p>
<p class='right'>TWELVE STEPS AND TWELVE TRADITIONS, p. 21</p>
<p><br><br>
When I was drinking all I could ever think about was &quot;I, I, I,&quot; or &quot;Me, Me, Me.&quot; Such painful obsession of self, such soul sickness, such spiritual selfishness bound me to the bottle for more than half my life.</p>
<p>The journey to find God and to do His will one day at a time began with the first word of the First Step . . . &quot;We.&quot; There was power in numbers, there was strength in numbers, there was safety in numbers, and for an alcoholic like me, there was life in numbers. If I had tried to recover alone I probably would have died. With God and another alcoholic I have a divine purpose in my life . . . I have become a channel for God's healing love.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 11:11:11 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 240521</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240521.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240521.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>A LIST OF BLESSINGS</p></h1>
<p><em>One exercise that I practice is to try for a full inventory of my blessings...</em></p>
<p class='right'>AS BILL SEES IT, p. 37</p>
<p><br><br>
What did I have to be grateful for? I shut myself up and started listing the blessings for which I was in no way responsible, beginning with having been born of sound mind and body. I went through seventy-four years of living right up to the present moment. The list ran to two pages, and took two hours to compile; I included health, family, money, A.A. – the whole gamut.</p>
<p>Every day in my prayers, I ask God to help me remember my list, and to be grateful for it throughout the day. When I remember my gratitude list, it's very hard to conclude that God is picking on me.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 11:11:11 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 240520</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240520.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240520.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>ONE DAY AT A TIME</p></h1>
<p><em>Above all, take it one day at a time.</em></p>
<p class='right'>AS BILL SEES IT, p. 11</p>
<p><br><br>
Why do I kid myself that I must stay away from a drink for only one day, when I know perfectly well I must never drink again as long as I live? I am not kidding myself because one day at a time is probably the only way I can reach the long-range objective of staying sober.</p>
<p>If I determine that I shall never drink again as long as I live, I set myself up. How can I be sure I won't drink when I have no idea what the future may hold?</p>
<p>On a day-at-a-time basis, I am confident I can stay away from a drink for one day. So I set out with confidence. At the end of the day, I have the reward of achievement. Achievement feels good and that makes me want more!</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 11:11:11 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 240519</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240519.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240519.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>GIVING WITHOUT STRINGS</p></h1>
<p><em>And he well knows that his own life has been made richer, as an extra dividend of giving to another without any demand for a return.</em></p>
<p class='right'>AS BILL SEES IT, p. 69</p>
<p><br><br>
The concept of giving without strings was hard to understand when I first came into the program. I was suspicious when others wanted to help me. I thought, &quot;What do they want in return?&quot; But I soon learned the joy of helping another alcoholic and I understood why they were there for me in the beginning. My attitudes changed and I wanted to help others. Sometimes I became anxious, as I wanted them to know the joys of sobriety, that life can be beautiful. When my life is full of a loving God of my understanding and I give that love to my fellow alcoholic, I feel a special richness that is hard to explain.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 11:11:11 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 240518</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240518.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240518.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>FREEDOM TO BE ME</p></h1>
<p><em>If we are painstaking about this phase of our development, we will be amazed before we are half way through. We are going to know a new freedom and a new happiness.</em></p>
<p class='right'>ALCOHOLICS ANONYMOUS, p. 83</p>
<p><br><br>
My first true freedom is the freedom not to have to take a drink today. If I truly want it, I will work the Twelve Steps and the happiness of this freedom will come to me through the Steps – sometimes quickly, sometimes slowly. Other freedoms will follow, and inventorying them is a new happiness. I had a new freedom today, the freedom to be me. I have the freedom to be the best me I have ever been.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 11:11:11 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 240517</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240517.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240517.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>. . . AND FORGIVE</p></h1>
<p><em>Under very trying conditions I have had, again and again, to forgive others – also myself.</em></p>
<p class='right'>AS BILL SEES IT, p. 268</p>
<p><br><br>
Forgiveness of self and forgiveness of others are just two currents in the same river, both hindered or shut off completely by the dam of resentment. Once that dam is lifted, both currents can flow. The Steps of A.A. allow me to see how resentment has built up and subsequently blocked off this flow in my life. The Steps provide a way by which my resentments may – by the grace of God as I understand Him – be lifted. It is as a result of this solution that I can find the necessary grace which enables me to forgive myself and others.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 11:11:11 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 240516</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240516.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240516.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>WE FORGIVE . . .</p></h1>
<p><em>Often it was while working on this Step with our sponsors or spiritual advisers that we first felt truly able to forgive others, no matter how deeply we felt they had wronged us.  Our moral inventory had persuaded us that all-round forgiveness was desirable, but it was only when we resolutely tackled Step Five that we inwardly knew we'd be able to receive forgiveness and give it, too.</em></p>
<p class='right'>TWELVE STEPS AND TWELVE TRADITIONS, p. 58</p>
<p><br><br>
What a great feeling forgiveness is! What a revelation about my emotional, psychological and spiritual nature. All it takes is willingness to forgive; God will do the rest.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 11:11:11 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 240515</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240515.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240515.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>KNOW GOD; KNOW PEACE</p></h1>
<p><em>It is plain that a life which includes deep resentment leads only to futility and unhappiness. . . . But with the alcoholic, whose hope is the maintenance and growth of a spiritual experience, this business of resentment is infinitely grave.</em></p>
<p class='right'>ALCOHOLICS ANONYMOUS, p. 66</p>
<p><br><br>
Know God;<br>
Know peace.<br>
No God;<br>
No peace.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 11:11:11 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 240514</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240514.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240514.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>IT'S OKAY TO BE ME</p></h1>
<p><em>Time after time newcomers have tried to keep to themselves certain facts about their lives. . . . they have turned to easier methods. . . . But they had not learned enough humility. . . .</em></p>
<p class='right'>ALCOHOLICS ANONYMOUS, pp. 72-73</p>
<p><br><br>
Humility sounds so much like humiliation, but it really is the ability to look at myself – and honestly accept what I find. I no longer need to be the &quot;smartest&quot; or &quot;dumbest&quot; or any other &quot;est.&quot; Finally, it is okay to be me. It is easier for me to accept myself if I share my whole life. If I cannot share in meetings, then I had better have a sponsor – someone with whom I can share those &quot;certain facts&quot; that could lead me back to a drunk, to death. I need to take all the Steps. I need the Fifth Step to learn true humility. Easier methods do not work.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 11:11:11 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 240513</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240513.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240513.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>THE EASIER, SOFTER WAY</p></h1>
<p><em>If we skip this vital step, we may not overcome drinking.</em></p>
<p class='right'>ALCOHOLICS ANONYMOUS, p. 72</p>
<p><br><br>
I certainly didn't leap at the opportunity to face who I was, especially when the pains of my drinking days hung over me like a dark cloud. But I soon heard at the meetings about the fellow member who just didn't want to take Step Five and kept coming back to meetings, trembling from the horrors of reliving his past. The easier, softer way is to take these Steps to freedom from our fatal disease, and to put our faith in the Fellowship and our Higher Power.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 11:11:11 EST</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
