<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>daily reflections</title>
<link>https://dailyreflections.co/</link>
<description>alcoholics anonymous daily reflections</description>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 240831</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240831.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240831.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>A UNIQUE PROGRAM</p></h1>
<p><em>Alcoholics Anonymous will never have a professional class. We have gained some understanding of the ancient words “Freely ye have received, freely give.” We have discovered that at the point of professionalism, money and spirituality do not mix.</em>
<br/></p>
<p class='right'>-TWELVE STEPS AND TWELVE TRADITIONS, p. 166</p>
<p><br><br>
I believe that Alcoholics Anonymous stands alone in the treatment of alcoholism because it is based solely on the principle of one alcoholic sharing with another alcoholic. This is what makes the program unique. When I decided that I wanted to stay sober, I called a woman who I knew was a sober member of A.A., and she carried the message of Alcoholics Anonymous to me. She received no monetary compensation, but rather was paid by staying sober another day herself. Today I could ask for no payment other than another day free from alcohol, so in that respect, I am generously paid for my labor.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 06:46:01 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 240830</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240830.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240830.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>THE ONLY REQUIREMENT …</p></h1>
<p><em>“At one time. . .every A.A. group had many membership rules.  Everybody was scared witless that something or somebody would capsize the boat. . .The total list was a mile long. If all those rules had been in effect everywhere, nobody could have possibly joined A.A. at all.”</em>
<br/></p>
<p class='right'>-TWELVE STEPS AND TWELVE TRADITIONS, p. 139-40</p>
<p><br><br>
I’m grateful that the Third Tradition only requires of me a desire to stop drinking. I had been breaking promises for years. In the Fellowship I didn’t have to make promises, I didn’t have to concentrate. It only required my attending one meeting, in a foggy condition, to know I was home. I didn’t have to pledge undying love. Here, strangers hugged me. “It gets better,” they said, and “One day at a time, you can do it.” They were no longer strangers, but caring friends. I ask God to help me to reach out to people desiring sobriety, and to, please, keep me grateful!</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 22:59:02 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 240829</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240829.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240829.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>I CHOOSE ANONYMITY</p></h1>
<p><em>We are sure that humility, expressed by anonymity, is the greatest safeguard that Alcoholics Anonymous can ever have.</em>
<br/></p>
<p class='right'>-12 &amp; 12, p.187</p>
<p><br><br>
Since there are no rules in A.A. I place myself where I want to be, and so I choose anonymity. I want my God to use me, humbly, as one of His tools in this program. Sacrifice is the art of giving of myself freely, allowing humility to replace my ego. With sobriety,  I suppress that urge to cry out to the world, “I am a member of A.A.” and I experience inner joy and peace. I let people see the changes in me and hope they will ask what happened to me. I place the principles of spirituality ahead of judging, fault-finding, and criticism. I want love and caring in my group, so I can grow.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 22:59:02 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 240828</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240828.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240828.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>LIGHTENING THE BURDEN</p></h1>
<p><em>Showing others who suffer how we were given help is the very thing which makes life seem so worth while to us now. The dark past is the key to life and happiness for others.</em>
<br/></p>
<p class='right'>-Alcoholics Anonymous, p.124</p>
<p><br><br>
Since I have been sober, I have been healed of many pains:  deceiving my partner, deserting my best friend, and spoiling my mother’s hopes for my life. In each case someone in the program told me of a similar problem, and I was able to share what happened to me. When my story was told, both of us got up with lighter hearts.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 19:17:01 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 240827</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240827.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240827.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>CENTERING OUR THOUGHTS</p></h1>
<p><em>When World War II broke out, our A.A. dependence on a Higher Power had its first major test. A.A.’s entered the services and were scattered all over the world. Would they be able to take the discipline, stand up under fire, and endure?</em>
<br/></p>
<p class='right'>-As Bill Sees It, p.200</p>
<p><br><br>
I will center my thoughts on a Higher Power. I will surrender all to this power within me. I will become a soldier for this power, feeling the might of the spiritual army as it exists in my life today. I will allow a wave of spiritual union to connect me through my gratitude, obedience and discipline to this Higher Power. Let me allow this power to lead me through the orders of the day. May the steps I take today strengthen my words and deeds, may I know that the message I carry is mine to share, given freely by this power greater than myself.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 21:59:02 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 240826</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240826.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240826.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>THE GIFT OF BONDING</p></h1>
<p><em>Relieve me of the bondage of self, that I may better do Thy will.</em>
<br/></p>
<p class='right'>-ALCOHOLICS ANONYMOUS , p. 63</p>
<p><br><br>
Many times in my alcoholic state, I drank to establish a bond between myself and others, but I succeeded only in establishing the bondage of alcoholic loneliness. Through the A.A. way of life, I have received the gift of bonding – with those who were there before me, with those who are there now, and with those yet to come. For this gracious gift from God, I am forever grateful.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 09:45:02 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 240825</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240825.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240825.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>THE GIFT OF BONDING</p></h1>
<p><em>Relieve me of the bondage of self, that I may better do Thy will.</em>
<br/></p>
<p class='right'>-ALCOHOLICS ANONYMOUS , p. 63</p>
<p><br><br>
Many times in my alcoholic state, I drank to establish a bond between myself and others, but I succeeded only in establishing the bondage of alcoholic loneliness. Through the A.A. way of life, I have received the gift of bonding – with those who were there before me, with those who are there now, and with those yet to come. For this gracious gift from God, I am forever grateful.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 21:59:02 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 240824</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240824.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240824.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>A RIDDLE THAT WORKS</p></h1>
<p><em>It may be possible to find explanations of spiritual experiences such as ours, but I have often tried to explain my own and have succeeded only in giving the story of it. I know the feeling it gave me and the results it has brought, but I realize I may never fully understand its deeper why and how.</em>
<br/></p>
<p class='right'>-AS BILL SEES IT, p. 313</p>
<p><br><br>
I had a profound spiritual experience during an open A.A. meeting, which led me to blurt out. “I’m an alcoholic!” I have not had a drink since that day. I can tell you the words I heard just prior to my admission, and how those words affected me, but as to why it happened, I do not know. I believe a power greater than myself chose me to recover, yet I do not know why. I try not to worry or wonder about what I do not yet know; instead, I trust that if I continue to work the Steps, practice the A.A. principles in my life, and share my story, I will be guided lovingly toward a deep and mature spirituality in which more will be revealed to me. For the time being, it is a gift for me to trust God, work the Steps and help others.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 21:33:41 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 240823</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240823.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240823.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>BRINGING THE MESSAGE HOME</p></h1>
<p><em>Can we bring the same spirit of love and tolerance into our sometimes deranged family lives that we bring to our A.A. group?</em>
<br/></p>
<p class='right'>-TWELVE STEPS AND TWELVE TRADITIONS , pp. 111 -112</p>
<p><br><br>
My family members suffer from the effects of my disease. Loving and accepting them as they are – just as I love and accept A.A. members – fosters a return of love, tolerance and harmony to my life. Using common courtesy and respecting other’s personal boundaries are necessary practices for all areas of my life.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 19:59:01 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 240822</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240822.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240822.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>SEEKING EMOTIONAL STABILITY, p.243</p></h1>
<p><em>When we developed still more, we discovered the best possible source of emotional stability to be God Himself. We found that dependence upon His perfect justice, forgiveness, and love was healthy, and that it would work where nothing else would. If we really depended upon God, we couldn’t very well play God to our fellows nor would we feel the urge wholly to rely on human protection and care.</em>
<br/></p>
<p class='right'>-12 &amp; 12, p.116</p>
<p><br><br>
All my life I depended on people for my emotional needs and security, but today I cannot live that way anymore. By the grace of God, I have admitted my powerlessness over people, places and things. I had been a real “people addict”; wherever I went there had to be someone who would pay some kind of attention to me. It was the kind of attitude that could only get worse, because the more I depended on others and demanded attention, the less I received. I have given up believing that any human power can relieve me of that empty feeling. Although I remain a fragile human being who needs to work A.A.’s Steps to keep this particular principle before my personality, it is only a loving God who can give me inner peace and emotional stability.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 22:00:18 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 240821</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240821.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240821.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>WE JUST TRY, p.242</p></h1>
<p><em>My stability came out of trying to give, not out of demanding that I receive.</em>
<br/></p>
<p class='right'>-The Best Of Bill, pp. 46-47</p>
<p><br><br>
As long as I try, with all my heart and soul, to pass along to others what has been passed along to me, and do not demand anything in return, life is good to me. Before entering this program of Alcoholics Anonymous I was never able to give without demanding something in return. Little did I know that, once I began to give freely of myself, I would begin to receive, without ever expecting or demanding anything at all. What I receive today is the gift of “stability,” as Bill did: stability in my A.A. program; within myself; but most of all, in my relationship with my Higher Power, whom I choose to call God.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 22:04:31 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 240820</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240820.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240820.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>TOWARD EMOTIONAL FREEDOM</p></h1>
<p><em>Since defective relations with other human beings have nearly always been the immediate cause of our woes, including our alcoholism, no field of investigation could yield more satisfying and valuable rewards than this one.</em>
<br/></p>
<p class='right'>-TWELVE STEPS AND TWELVE TRADITIONS , p. 80</p>
<p><br><br>
Willingness is a peculiar thing for me in that, over a period of time, it seems to come, first with awareness, but then with a feeling of discomfort, making me want to take some action. As I reflected on taking the Eighth Step, my willingness to make amends to others came as a desire for forgiveness, of others and myself.</p>
<p>I felt forgiveness toward others after I became aware of my part in the difficulties of relationships. I wanted to feel the peace and serenity described in the Promises. From working the first seven Steps, I became aware of whom I had harmed and that I had been my own worst enemy. In order to restore my relationships with my fellow human beings, I knew I would have to change. I wanted to learn to live in harmony with myself and others so that I could also live in emotional freedom. The beginning of the end to my isolation – from my fellows and from God – came when I wrote my Eighth Step list.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 21:45:06 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 240819</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240819.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240819.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>A FRAME OF REFERENCE</p></h1>
<p><em>Referring to our list [inventory] again. Putting out of our minds the wrongs others had done, we resolutely looked for our own mistakes.  Where had we been selfish, dishonest, self-seeking and frightened?</em>
<br/></p>
<p class='right'>-ALCOHOLICS ANONYMOUS, p. 67</p>
<p><br><br>
There is a wonderful freedom in not needing constant approval from colleagues at work or from the people I love. I wish I had known about this Step before, because once I developed a frame of reference, I felt able to do the next right thing, knowing that the action fit the situation and that it was the correct thing to do.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 21:59:02 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 240818</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240818.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240818.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>GETTING WELL, p.239</p></h1>
<p><em>Very deep, sometimes quite forgotten, damaging emotional conflicts persist below the level of consciousness.</em>
<br/></p>
<p class='right'>-12 &amp; 12, pp. 79-80</p>
<p><br><br>
Only through positive action can I remove the remains of guilt and shame brought on by alcohol. Throughout my misadventures when I drank, my friends would say, “Why are you doing this? You’re only hurting yourself.” Little did I know how true were those words. Although I harmed others, some of my behavior caused grave wounds to my soul. Step Eight provides me with a way of forgiving myself. I alleviate much of the hidden damage when I make my list of those I have hurt. In making amends, I free myself of burdens, thus contributing to my healing.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 22:07:40 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 240817</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240817.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240817.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>RIGHTING THE HARM</p></h1>
<p><em>In many instances we shall find that though the harm done others has not been great, the emotional harm we have done ourselves has.</em>
<br/></p>
<p class='right'>-TWELVE STEPS AND TWELVE TRADITIONS, p. 79</p>
<p><br><br>
Have you ever thought that the harm you did a business associate, or perhaps a family member, was so slight that it really didn’t deserve an apology because they probably wouldn’t remember it anyway? If that person, and the wrong done to him, keeps coming to mind, time and again, causing an uneasy or perhaps guilty feeling, then I put that person’s name at the top of my “amends list,” and become willing to make a sincere apology, knowing I will feel calm and relaxed about that person once this very important part of my recovery is accomplished.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2024 21:59:01 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 240816</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240816.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240816.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>“I HAD DROPPED OUT”</p></h1>
<p><em>We might next ask ourselves what we mean when we say that we have “harmed” other people. What kinds of “harm” do people do one another, anyway? To define the word “harm” in a practical way, we might call it the result of instincts in collision, which cause physical, mental, emotional, or spiritual damage to people.</em>
<br/></p>
<p class='right'>-TWELVE STEPS AND TWELVE TRADITIONS , p. 80</p>
<p><br><br>
I had been to Eighth Step meetings, always thinking, “I really haven’t harmed many people, mostly myself.” But the time came when I wrote my list out and it was not as short as I thought it would be. I either liked you, disliked you, or needed something from you – it was that simple. People hadn’t done what I wanted them to do and intimate relationships were out of hand because of my partners unreasonable demands. Were these “sins of omission”? Because of my drinking, I had “dropped out” – never sending cards, returning calls, being there for other people, or taking part in their lives.  What a grace it has been to look at these relationships, to make my inventories in quiet, alone with the God of my understanding, and to go forth daily, with a willingness to be honest and forthright in my relationships.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 21:59:02 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 240815</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240815.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240815.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>DIDN’T WE HURT ANYBODY?</p></h1>
<p><em>Some of us, though, tripped over a very different snag. We clung to the claim that when drinking we never hurt anybody but ourselves.</em>
<br/></p>
<p class='right'>TWELVE STEPS AND TWELVE TRADITIONS , p. 79</p>
<p><br><br>
This Step seemed so simple. I identified several people whom I had harmed, but they were no longer available. Still, I was uneasy about the Step and avoided conversations dealing with it. In time I learned to investigate those Steps and areas of my life which made me uncomfortable. My search revealed my parents, who had been deeply hurt by my isolation from them; my employer, who worried about my absences, my memory lapses, my temper; and the friends I had shunned, without explanation. As I faced the reality of the harm I had done, Step Eight took on a new meaning. I am no longer uncomfortable and I feel clean and light.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 21:42:02 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 240814</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240814.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240814.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>REDOUBLING OUR EFFORTS</p></h1>
<p><em>To a degree, he has already done this when taking moral inventory, but now the time has come when he ought to redouble his efforts to see how many people he had hurt, and in what ways.</em>
<br/></p>
<p class='right'>TWELVE STEPS AND TWELVE TRADITIONS , p. 77</p>
<p><br><br>
As I continue to grow in sobriety, I become more aware of myself as a person of worth. In the process, I am better able to see others as persons, and with this comes the realization that these were people whom I had hurt in my drinking days. I didn’t just lie, I lied about Tom. I didn’t just cheat, I cheated Joe. What were seemingly impersonal acts, were really personal affronts, because it was people – people of worth – whom I had harmed. I need to do something about the people I have hurt so that I may enjoy a peaceful sobriety.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 21:42:02 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 240813</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240813.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240813.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>A CLEAN SWEEP</p></h1>
<p><em>… and third, having thus cleaned away the debris of the past, we consider how, with our newfound knowledge of ourselves, we may develop the best possible relations with every human being we know.</em>
<br/></p>
<p class='right'>TWELVE STEPS AND TWELVE TRADITIONS , p. 77</p>
<p><br><br>
As I face the Eighth Step, everything that was required for successful completion of the previous seven Steps came together: courage, honesty, sincerity, willingness and thoroughness. I could not muster the strength required for this task at the beginning, which is why this Step reads “Became willing … ”</p>
<p>I needed to develop the courage to begin, the honesty to see where I was wrong, a sincere desire to set things right, thoroughness in making a list, and willingness to take the risk required for true humility. With the help of my Higher Power in developing these virtues, I completed this Step and continued to move forward in my quest for spiritual growth.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 13:16:02 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 240812</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240812.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240812.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>A LOOK BACKWARD</p></h1>
<p><em>First, we take a look backward and try to discover where we have been at fault; next we make a vigorous attempt to repair the damage we have done; …</em>
<br/></p>
<p class='right'>TWELVE STEPS AND TWELVE TRADITIONS, p. 77</p>
<p><br><br>
As a traveler on a fresh and exciting A.A. journey of recovery, I experienced a newfound peace of mind and the horizon appeared clear and bright, rather than obscure and dim. Reviewing my life to discover where I had been at fault seemed to be such an arduous and dangerous task. It was painful to pause and look backward. I was afraid I might stumble! Couldn’t I put the past out of my mind and just live in my new golden present? I realized that those in the past whom I had harmed stood between me and my desire to continue my movement toward serenity. I had to ask for courage to face those persons from my life who still lived in my conscience, to recognize and deal with the guilt that their presence produced in me. I had to look at the damage I had done, and become willing to make amends. Only then could my journey of the spirit resume.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 21:49:02 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 240811</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240811.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240811.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>REMOVING “THE GROUND GLASS”</p></h1>
<p><em>The moral inventory is a cool examination of the damages that occurred to us during life and a sincere effort to look at them in a true perspective. This has the effect of taking the ground glass out of us, the emotional substance that still cuts and inhibits.</em>
<br/></p>
<p class='right'>AS BILL SEES IT, p. 140</p>
<p><br><br>
My Eighth Step list used to drag me into a whirlpool of resentment. After four years of sobriety, I was blocked by denial connected with an ongoing abusive relationship. The argument between fear and pride eased as the words of the Step moved from my head to my heart. For the first time in years I opened my box of paints and poured out an honest rage, an explosion of reds and blacks and yellows. As I looked at the drawing, tears of joy and relief flowed down my cheeks.  In my disease, I had given up my art, a self-inflicted punishment far greater than any imposed from outside. In my recovery, I learned that the pain of my defects is the very substance God uses to cleanse my character and to set me free.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 21:50:03 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 240810</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240810.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240810.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>REDOUBLING OUR EFFORTS</p></h1>
<p><em>To a degree, he has already done this when taking moral inventory, but now the time has come when he ought to redouble his efforts to see how many people he had hurt, and in what ways.</em>
<br/></p>
<p class='right'>-TWELVE STEPS AND TWELVE TRADITIONS , p. 77</p>
<p><br><br>
REDOUBLING OUR EFFORTS</p>
<p>As I continue to grow in sobriety, I become more aware of myself as a person of worth. In the process, I am better able to see others as persons, and with this comes the realization that these were people whom I had hurt in my drinking days. I didn’t just lie, I lied about Tom. I didn’t just cheat, I cheated Joe. What were seemingly impersonal acts, were really personal affronts, because it was people – people of worth – whom I had harmed. I need to do something about the people I have hurt so that I may enjoy a peaceful sobriety.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 15:59:01 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 240809</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240809.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240809.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>“ … OF ALL PERSONS WE HAD HARMED”</p></h1>
<p><em>“ … and became willing to make amends to them all.”</em>
<br/></p>
<p class='right'>TWELVE STEPS AND TWELVE TRADITIONS, p. 77</p>
<p><br><br>
One of the key words in the Eighth Step is the word all. I am not free to select a few names for the list and to disregard others. It is a list of all persons I have harmed. I can see immediately that this Step entails forgiveness because if I’m not willing to forgive someone, there is little chance I will place his name on the list. Before I placed the first name on my list, I said a little prayer: “I forgive anyone and everyone who has ever harmed me at any time and under any circumstances.”  It is well for me to contemplate a small, but very significant, two-letter word every time the Lord’s Prayer is said. The word is as. I ask, “Forgive us our trespasses, as we forgive those who trespass against us.” In this case, as means, “in the same manner.” I am asking to be forgiven in the same manner that I forgive others. As I say this portion of the prayer, if I am harboring hatred or resentment, I am inviting more resentment, when I should be calling on the spirit of forgiveness.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 15:59:01 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 240808</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240808.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240808.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>MADE A LIST … ”</p></h1>
<p><em>Made a list of all persons we had harmed.</em>
<br/></p>
<p class='right'>-TWELVE STEPS AND TWELVE TRADITIONS  p. 77</p>
<p><br><br>
When I approached the Eighth Step, I wondered how I could list all the things that I have done to other people since there were so many people, and some of them weren’t alive anymore. Some of the hurts I inflicted weren’t bad, but they really bothered me. The main thing to see in this Step was to become willing to do whatever I had to do to make these amends to the best of my ability at that particular time. Where there is a will, there’s a way, so if I want to feel better, I need to unload the guilt feeling I have. A peaceful mind has no room for feeling of guilt. With the help of my Higher Power, if I am honest with myself, I can cleanse my mind of these feelings.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 22:06:35 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 240807</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240807.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240807.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>A “DESIGN FOR LIVING”</p></h1>
<p><em>We in our turn, sought the same escape with all the desperation of drowning men. What seemed at first a flimsy reed, has proved to be the loving and powerful hand of God. A new life has been given us or, if you prefer, “a design for living” that really works.</em>
<br/></p>
 <p class='right'>-ALCOHOLIC ANONYMOUS , p. 28</p>
<p><br><br>
I try each day to raise my heart and hands in thanks to God for showing me a “design for living” that really works through our beautiful Fellowship. But what, exactly, is this “design for living” that “really works”? For me, it is the practice of the Twelve Steps to the best of my ability, the continued awareness of a God who loves me unconditionally, and the hope that, in each new day, there is a purpose for my being. I am truly, truly blessed in the Fellowship.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 21:59:02 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 240806</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240806.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240806.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>DRIVEN</p></h1>
<p><em>Driven by a hundred forms of fear, self-delusion, self-seeking and self-pity, we step on the toes of our fellows and they retaliate.</em>
<br/></p>
 <p class='right'>-ALCOHOLIC ANONYMOUS , p. 62</p>
<p><br><br>
My selfishness was the driving force behind my drinking. I drank to celebrate success and I drank to drown my sorrows. Humility is the answer. I learn to turn my will and my life over to the care of God. My sponsor tells me that service keeps me sober. Today I ask myself:  Have I sought knowledge of God’s will for me? Have I done service for my A. A. group?</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 23:00:00 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 240805</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240805.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240805.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>LISTENING DEEPLY, p.226</p></h1>
<p><em>How persistently we claim the right to decide all by ourselves just what we shall think and just how we shall act.</em>
<br/></p>
 <p class='right'>-TWELVE STEPS AND TWELVE TRADITIONS, p. 37</p>
<p><br><br>
If I accept and act upon the advice of those who have made the program work for themselves, I have a chance to outgrow the limits of the past. Some problems will shrink to nothingness, while others may require patient, well-thought-out action. Listening deeply when others share can develop intuition in handling problems which arise unexpectedly. It is usually best for me to avoid impetuous action.  Attending a meeting or calling a fellow A.A. member will usually reduce tension enough to bring relief to a desperate sufferer like me. Sharing problems at meetings with other alcoholics to whom I can relate, or privately with my sponsor, can change aspects of the positions in which I find myself. Character defects are identified and I begin to see how they work against me. When I put my faith in the spiritual power of the program, when I trust others to teach me what I need to do to have a better life, I find that I can trust myself to do what is necessary.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 23:00:00 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 240804</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240804.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240804.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>SEEDS OF FAITH</p></h1>
<p><em>Faith, to be sure, is necessary, but faith alone can avail nothing. We can have faith, yet keep God out of our lives.</em>
<br/></p>
 <p class='right'>-TWELVE STEPS AND TWELVE TRADITIONS, p. 34</p>
<p><br><br>
As a child I constantly questioned the existence of God. To a “scientific thinker” like me, no answer could withstand a thorough dissection, until a very patient woman finally said to me, “You must have faith.” With that simple statement, the seeds of my recovery were sown!</p>
<p>Today, as I practice my recovery — cutting back the weeds of alcoholism — slowly I am letting those early seeds of faith to grow and bloom. Each day of recovery, of ardent gardening, brings the Higher Power of my understanding more fully into my life. My God has always been with me through faith, but it is my responsibility to have the willingness to accept His presence. I ask God to grant me the willingness to do His will.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 23:00:00 EST</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
