<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>daily reflections</title>
<link>https://dailyreflections.co/</link>
<description>alcoholics anonymous daily reflections</description>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 240822</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240822.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240822.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>SEEKING EMOTIONAL STABILITY, p.243</p></h1>
<p><em>When we developed still more, we discovered the best possible source of emotional stability to be God Himself. We found that dependence upon His perfect justice, forgiveness, and love was healthy, and that it would work where nothing else would. If we really depended upon God, we couldn’t very well play God to our fellows nor would we feel the urge wholly to rely on human protection and care.</em>
<br/></p>
<p class='right'>-12 &amp; 12, p.116</p>
<p><br><br>
All my life I depended on people for my emotional needs and security, but today I cannot live that way anymore. By the grace of God, I have admitted my powerlessness over people, places and things. I had been a real “people addict”; wherever I went there had to be someone who would pay some kind of attention to me. It was the kind of attitude that could only get worse, because the more I depended on others and demanded attention, the less I received. I have given up believing that any human power can relieve me of that empty feeling. Although I remain a fragile human being who needs to work A.A.’s Steps to keep this particular principle before my personality, it is only a loving God who can give me inner peace and emotional stability.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 23:00:18 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 240821</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240821.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240821.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>WE JUST TRY, p.242</p></h1>
<p><em>My stability came out of trying to give, not out of demanding that I receive.</em>
<br/></p>
<p class='right'>-The Best Of Bill, pp. 46-47</p>
<p><br><br>
As long as I try, with all my heart and soul, to pass along to others what has been passed along to me, and do not demand anything in return, life is good to me. Before entering this program of Alcoholics Anonymous I was never able to give without demanding something in return. Little did I know that, once I began to give freely of myself, I would begin to receive, without ever expecting or demanding anything at all. What I receive today is the gift of “stability,” as Bill did: stability in my A.A. program; within myself; but most of all, in my relationship with my Higher Power, whom I choose to call God.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 23:04:31 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 241101</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/241101.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/241101.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>I CANNOT CHANGE THE WIND</p></h1>
<p><em>“It is easy to let up on the spiritual program of action and rest on our laurels. We are headed for trouble if we do, for alcohol is a subtle foe.”</em>
<br/></p>
<p class='right'>-ALCOHOLICS ANONYMOUS, p. 85</p>
<p><br><br>
My first sponsor told me there were two things to say about prayer and meditation: first, I had to start and second, I had to continue. When I came to A.A. my spiritual life was bankrupt; if I considered God at all, He was to be called upon only when my self-will was incapable of a task or when overwhelming fears had eroded my ego.</p>
<p>Today I am grateful for a new life, one in which my prayers are those of thanksgiving.  My prayer time is more for listening than for talking. I know today that if I cannot change the wind, I can adjust my sail. I know the difference between superstition and spirituality. I know there is a graceful way of being right, and many ways to be wrong.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 12:17:02 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 241031</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/241031.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/241031.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>AVOIDING CONTROVERSY</p></h1>
<p><em>All history affords us the spectacle of striving nations and groups finally torn asunder because they were designed for, or tempted into, controversy. Others fell apart because of sheer self-righteousness while trying to enforce upon the rest of mankind some millennium of their own specification.</em>
<br/></p>
<p class='right'>-TWELVE STEPS AND TWELVE TRADITIONS, p. 176</p>
<p><br><br>
As an A.A. member and sponsor, I know I can cause real damage if I yield to temptation and give opinions and advice on another’s medical, marital, or religious problems. I am not a doctor, counselor, or lawyer. I cannot tell anyone how he or she should live; however, I can share how I came through similar situations without drinking, and how A.A.’s Steps and Traditions help me in dealing with my life.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 20:59:02 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 241030</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/241030.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/241030.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>LIVE AND LET LIVE</p></h1>
<p><em>Never since it began has Alcoholics Anonymous been divided by a major controversial issue. Nor has our Fellowship ever publicly taken sides on any question in an embattled world. This, however, has been no earned virtue. It could almost be said that we were born with it. “So long as we don’t argue these matters privately, it’s a cinch we never shall publicly. ”</em>
<br/></p>
<p class='right'>-TWELVE STEPS AND TWELVE TRADITIONS, p. 176</p>
<p><br><br>
Do I remember that I have a right to my opinion but that others don’t have to share it?  That’s the spirit of “Live and Let Live.” The Serenity Prayer reminds me, with God’s help, to “Accept the things I cannot change.” Am I still trying to change others? When it comes to “Courage to change the things I can,” do I remember that my opinions are mine, and yours are yours? Am I still afraid to be me? When it comes to “Wisdom to know the difference,” do I remember that my opinions come from my experience?  If I have a know-it-all attitude, aren’t I being deliberately controversial?</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 16:59:02 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 241029</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/241029.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/241029.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>OUR SURVIVAL</p></h1>
<p><em>Since recovery from alcoholism is life itself to us, it is imperative that we preserve in full strength our means of survival.</em>
<br/></p>
<p class='right'>-TWELVE STEPS AND TWELVE TRADITIONS, p. 177</p>
<p><br><br>
The honesty expressed by the members of A.A. in meetings has the power to open my mind. Nothing can block the flow of energy that honesty carries with it. The only obstacle to this flow of energy is inebriation, but even then, no one will find a closed door if he or she has left and chooses to return. Once he or she has received the gift of sobriety, each A.A. member is challenged on a daily basis to accept a program of honesty. My Higher Power created me for a purpose in life. I ask him to accept my honest efforts to continue on my journey in the spiritual way of life. I call on Him for strength to know and seek His will.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 20:44:02 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 241028</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/241028.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/241028.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>AN UNBROKEN TRADITION</p></h1>
<p><em>We conceive the survival and spread of Alcoholics Anonymous to be something of far greater importance than the weight we could collectively throw back of any other cause.</em>
<br/></p>
<p class='right'>-TWELVE STEPS AND TWELVE TRADITIONS, p. 177</p>
<p><br><br>
How much it means to me that an unbroken tradition of more than half a century is a thread that connects me to Bill W. and Dr. Bob. How much more grounded I feel to be in a Fellowship whose aims are constant and unflagging. I am grateful that the energies of A.A. have never been scattered, but focused instead on our members and on individual sobriety. My beliefs are what make me human; I am free to hold any opinion, but A.A.’s purpose — so clearly stated fifty years ago — is for me to keep sober. That purpose has promoted round-the-clock meeting schedules, and the thousands of intergroup and central service offices, with their thousands of volunteers. Like the sun focused through a magnifying glass, A.A.’s single vision has lit a fire of faith in sobriety in millions of hearts, including mine.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 20:59:01 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 241027</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/241027.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/241027.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>GLOBAL SHARING</p></h1>
<p><em>The only thing that matters is that he is an alcoholic who has found a key to sobriety.  These legacies of suffering and of recovery are easily passed among alcoholics, one to the other. This is our gift from God, and its bestowal upon others like us is the one aim that today animates A.A.’s all around the globe.</em>
<br/></p>
<p class='right'>-TWELVE STEPS AND TWELVE TRADITIONS, p. 151</p>
<p><br><br>
The strength of Alcoholics Anonymous lies in the desire of each member and of each group around the world to share with other alcoholics their suffering and the steps taken to gain, and maintain, recovery. By keeping a conscious contact with my Higher Power, I make sure that I always nurture my desire to help other alcoholics, thus insuring the continuity of the wonderful fraternity of Alcoholics Anonymous.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 20:59:01 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 241026</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/241026.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/241026.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>ONE ULTIMATE AUTHORITY</p></h1>
<p><em>For our group purpose there is but one ultimate authority—a loving God as He may express Himself in our group conscience.</em>
<br/></p>
<p class='right'>-TWELVE STEPS AND TWELVE TRADITIONS, p. 132</p>
<p><br><br>
When I am chosen to carry some small responsibility for my fellows, I ask that God grant me the patience, open-mindedness, and willingness to listen to those I would lead. I must remind myself that I am the trusted servant of others, not their “governor,” “teacher,” or “instructor.” God guides my words and my actions, and my responsibility is to heed His suggestions. Trust is my watchword, I trust others who lead. In the Fellowship of A.A., I entrust God with the ultimate authority of “running the show.”</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 20:49:01 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 241025</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/241025.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/241025.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>A.A.’s HEARTBEAT</p></h1>
<p><em>Without unity, the heart of A.A. would cease to beat;</em>
<br/></p>
<p class='right'>-AS BILL SEES IT, p. 125</p>
<p><br><br>
Without unity I would be unable to recover in A.A. on a daily basis. By practicing unity within my group, with other A.A. members and at all levels of this great Fellowship, I receive a pronounced feeling of knowing that I am a part of a miracle that was divinely inspired. The ability of Bill W. and Dr. Bob, working together and passing it on to other members, tells me that to give it away is to keep it. Unity is oneness and yet the whole Fellowship is for all of us.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 20:59:02 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 241024</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/241024.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/241024.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>“BY FAITH AND BY WORKS”</p></h1>
<p><em>On anvils of experience, the structure of our Society was hammered out. Thus has it been with A.A. By faith and by works we have been able to build upon the lessons of an incredible experience. They live today in the Twelve Traditions of Alcoholics Anonymous, which – God willing – shall sustain us in unity for so long as He may need us.</em>
<br/></p>
<p class='right'>-TWELVE STEPS AND TWELVE TRADITIONS, p. 131</p>
<p><br><br>
God has allowed me the right to be wrong in order for our Fellowship to exist as it does today. If I place God’s will first in my life, it is very likely that A.A. as I know it today will remain as it is.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 20:02:02 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 241023</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/241023.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/241023.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>WHAT WE KNOW BEST</p></h1>
<p><em>“Shoemaker, stick to thy last!” … better do one thing supremely well than many badly.  That is the central theme of this Tradition [Five]. Around it our Society gathers in unity.  The very life of our Fellowship requires the preservation of this principle.</em>
<br/></p>
<p class='right'>-TWELVE STEPS AND TWELVE TRADITIONS, p. 150</p>
<p><br><br>
The survival of A.A. depends upon unity. What would happen if a group decided to become an employment agency, a treatment center or a social service agency? Too much specialization leads to no specialization, to frittering of efforts and, finally, to decline. I have the qualifications to share my sufferings and my way of recovery with the newcomer.  Conformity to A.A.’s primary purpose insures the safety of the wonderful gift of sobriety, so my responsibility is enormous. The life of millions of alcoholics is closely tied to my competence in “carrying the message to the still-suffering alcoholic.”</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 20:59:02 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 241022</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/241022.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/241022.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>TRUE TOLERANCE</p></h1>
<p><em>Finally, we begin to see that all people, including ourselves, are to some extent emotionally ill as well as frequently wrong, and then we approach true tolerance and see what real love for our fellows actually means.</em>
<br/></p>
<p class='right'>-TWELVE STEPS AND TWELVE TRADITIONS, p. 92</p>
<p><br><br>
The thought occurred to me that all people are emotionally ill to some extent. How could we not be? Who among us is spiritually perfect? Who among us is physically perfect?  How could any of us be emotionally perfect? Therefore, what else are we to do but bear with one another and treat each other as we would be treated in similar circumstances?  That is what love really is.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 20:59:01 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 241021</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/241021.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/241021.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>NOTHING GROWS IN THE DARK</p></h1>
<p><em>We will want the good that is in us all, even in the worst of us, to flower and to grow.</em>
<br/></p>
<p class='right'>-AS BILL SEES IT, p. 10</p>
<p><br><br>
With the self-discipline and insight gained from practicing Step Ten, I begin to know the gratifications of sobriety — not as mere abstinence from alcohol, but as recovery in every department of my life.</p>
<p>I renew hope, regenerate faith, and regain the dignity of self-respect. I discover the word “and” in the phrase “and when we were wrong, promptly admitted it.”Reassured that I am no longer always wrong, I learn to accept myself as I am, with a new sense of the miracles of sobriety and serenity.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 20:59:23 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 241020</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/241020.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/241020.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>SOLACE FOR CONFUSION</p></h1>
<p><em>Obviously, the dilemma of the wanderer from faith is that of profound confusion. He thinks himself lost to the comfort of any conviction at all. He cannot attain in even a small degree the assurance of the believer, the agnostic, or the atheist. He is the bewildered one.</em>
<br/></p>
<p class='right'>-TWELVE STEPS AND TWELVE TRADITIONS, p. 28</p>
<p><br><br>
The concept of God was one that I struggled with during my early years of sobriety. The images that came to me, conjured from my past, were heavy with fear, rejection and condemnation. Then I heard my friend Ed’s image of a Higher Power: As a boy he had been allowed a litter of puppies, provided that he assume responsibility for their care.  Each morning he would find the unavoidable “byproducts” of the puppies on the kitchen floor. Despite frustration, Ed said he couldn’t get angry because “that’s the nature of puppies.” Ed felt that God viewed our defects and shortcomings with a similar understanding and warmth. I’ve often found solace from my personal confusion in Ed’s calming concept of God.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 20:54:01 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 241019</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/241019.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/241019.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>A. A.’S “MAIN TAPROOT”</p></h1>
<p><em>The principle that we shall find no enduring strength until we first admit complete defeat is the main taproot from which our whole Society has sprung and flowered.</em>
<br/></p>
<p class='right'>-TWELVE STEPS AND TWELVE TRADITIONS, pp. 21-22</p>
<p><br><br>
Defeated, and knowing it, I arrived at the doors of A.A., alone and afraid of the unknown.  A power outside of myself had picked me up off my bed, guided me to the phone book, then to the bus stop, and through the doors of Alcoholics Anonymous. Once inside A.A. I experienced a sense of being loved and accepted, something I had not felt since early childhood. May I never lose the sense of wonder I experienced on that first evening with A.A., the greatest event of my entire life.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 20:26:05 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 241018</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/241018.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/241018.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 240820</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240820.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240820.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>TOWARD EMOTIONAL FREEDOM</p></h1>
<p><em>Since defective relations with other human beings have nearly always been the immediate cause of our woes, including our alcoholism, no field of investigation could yield more satisfying and valuable rewards than this one.</em>
<br/></p>
<p class='right'>-TWELVE STEPS AND TWELVE TRADITIONS , p. 80</p>
<p><br><br>
Willingness is a peculiar thing for me in that, over a period of time, it seems to come, first with awareness, but then with a feeling of discomfort, making me want to take some action. As I reflected on taking the Eighth Step, my willingness to make amends to others came as a desire for forgiveness, of others and myself.</p>
<p>I felt forgiveness toward others after I became aware of my part in the difficulties of relationships. I wanted to feel the peace and serenity described in the Promises. From working the first seven Steps, I became aware of whom I had harmed and that I had been my own worst enemy. In order to restore my relationships with my fellow human beings, I knew I would have to change. I wanted to learn to live in harmony with myself and others so that I could also live in emotional freedom. The beginning of the end to my isolation – from my fellows and from God – came when I wrote my Eighth Step list.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 22:45:06 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 240819</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240819.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240819.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>A FRAME OF REFERENCE</p></h1>
<p><em>Referring to our list [inventory] again. Putting out of our minds the wrongs others had done, we resolutely looked for our own mistakes.  Where had we been selfish, dishonest, self-seeking and frightened?</em>
<br/></p>
<p class='right'>-ALCOHOLICS ANONYMOUS, p. 67</p>
<p><br><br>
There is a wonderful freedom in not needing constant approval from colleagues at work or from the people I love. I wish I had known about this Step before, because once I developed a frame of reference, I felt able to do the next right thing, knowing that the action fit the situation and that it was the correct thing to do.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 22:59:02 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 240818</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240818.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240818.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>GETTING WELL, p.239</p></h1>
<p><em>Very deep, sometimes quite forgotten, damaging emotional conflicts persist below the level of consciousness.</em>
<br/></p>
<p class='right'>-12 &amp; 12, pp. 79-80</p>
<p><br><br>
Only through positive action can I remove the remains of guilt and shame brought on by alcohol. Throughout my misadventures when I drank, my friends would say, “Why are you doing this? You’re only hurting yourself.” Little did I know how true were those words. Although I harmed others, some of my behavior caused grave wounds to my soul. Step Eight provides me with a way of forgiving myself. I alleviate much of the hidden damage when I make my list of those I have hurt. In making amends, I free myself of burdens, thus contributing to my healing.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 23:07:40 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 240817</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240817.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240817.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>RIGHTING THE HARM</p></h1>
<p><em>In many instances we shall find that though the harm done others has not been great, the emotional harm we have done ourselves has.</em>
<br/></p>
<p class='right'>-TWELVE STEPS AND TWELVE TRADITIONS, p. 79</p>
<p><br><br>
Have you ever thought that the harm you did a business associate, or perhaps a family member, was so slight that it really didn’t deserve an apology because they probably wouldn’t remember it anyway? If that person, and the wrong done to him, keeps coming to mind, time and again, causing an uneasy or perhaps guilty feeling, then I put that person’s name at the top of my “amends list,” and become willing to make a sincere apology, knowing I will feel calm and relaxed about that person once this very important part of my recovery is accomplished.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2024 22:59:01 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 240816</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240816.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240816.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>“I HAD DROPPED OUT”</p></h1>
<p><em>We might next ask ourselves what we mean when we say that we have “harmed” other people. What kinds of “harm” do people do one another, anyway? To define the word “harm” in a practical way, we might call it the result of instincts in collision, which cause physical, mental, emotional, or spiritual damage to people.</em>
<br/></p>
<p class='right'>-TWELVE STEPS AND TWELVE TRADITIONS , p. 80</p>
<p><br><br>
I had been to Eighth Step meetings, always thinking, “I really haven’t harmed many people, mostly myself.” But the time came when I wrote my list out and it was not as short as I thought it would be. I either liked you, disliked you, or needed something from you – it was that simple. People hadn’t done what I wanted them to do and intimate relationships were out of hand because of my partners unreasonable demands. Were these “sins of omission”? Because of my drinking, I had “dropped out” – never sending cards, returning calls, being there for other people, or taking part in their lives.  What a grace it has been to look at these relationships, to make my inventories in quiet, alone with the God of my understanding, and to go forth daily, with a willingness to be honest and forthright in my relationships.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 22:59:02 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 240815</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240815.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240815.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>DIDN’T WE HURT ANYBODY?</p></h1>
<p><em>Some of us, though, tripped over a very different snag. We clung to the claim that when drinking we never hurt anybody but ourselves.</em>
<br/></p>
<p class='right'>TWELVE STEPS AND TWELVE TRADITIONS , p. 79</p>
<p><br><br>
This Step seemed so simple. I identified several people whom I had harmed, but they were no longer available. Still, I was uneasy about the Step and avoided conversations dealing with it. In time I learned to investigate those Steps and areas of my life which made me uncomfortable. My search revealed my parents, who had been deeply hurt by my isolation from them; my employer, who worried about my absences, my memory lapses, my temper; and the friends I had shunned, without explanation. As I faced the reality of the harm I had done, Step Eight took on a new meaning. I am no longer uncomfortable and I feel clean and light.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 22:42:02 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 240814</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240814.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240814.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>REDOUBLING OUR EFFORTS</p></h1>
<p><em>To a degree, he has already done this when taking moral inventory, but now the time has come when he ought to redouble his efforts to see how many people he had hurt, and in what ways.</em>
<br/></p>
<p class='right'>TWELVE STEPS AND TWELVE TRADITIONS , p. 77</p>
<p><br><br>
As I continue to grow in sobriety, I become more aware of myself as a person of worth. In the process, I am better able to see others as persons, and with this comes the realization that these were people whom I had hurt in my drinking days. I didn’t just lie, I lied about Tom. I didn’t just cheat, I cheated Joe. What were seemingly impersonal acts, were really personal affronts, because it was people – people of worth – whom I had harmed. I need to do something about the people I have hurt so that I may enjoy a peaceful sobriety.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 22:42:02 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 240813</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240813.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240813.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>A CLEAN SWEEP</p></h1>
<p><em>… and third, having thus cleaned away the debris of the past, we consider how, with our newfound knowledge of ourselves, we may develop the best possible relations with every human being we know.</em>
<br/></p>
<p class='right'>TWELVE STEPS AND TWELVE TRADITIONS , p. 77</p>
<p><br><br>
As I face the Eighth Step, everything that was required for successful completion of the previous seven Steps came together: courage, honesty, sincerity, willingness and thoroughness. I could not muster the strength required for this task at the beginning, which is why this Step reads “Became willing … ”</p>
<p>I needed to develop the courage to begin, the honesty to see where I was wrong, a sincere desire to set things right, thoroughness in making a list, and willingness to take the risk required for true humility. With the help of my Higher Power in developing these virtues, I completed this Step and continued to move forward in my quest for spiritual growth.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 14:16:02 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 240812</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240812.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240812.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>A LOOK BACKWARD</p></h1>
<p><em>First, we take a look backward and try to discover where we have been at fault; next we make a vigorous attempt to repair the damage we have done; …</em>
<br/></p>
<p class='right'>TWELVE STEPS AND TWELVE TRADITIONS, p. 77</p>
<p><br><br>
As a traveler on a fresh and exciting A.A. journey of recovery, I experienced a newfound peace of mind and the horizon appeared clear and bright, rather than obscure and dim. Reviewing my life to discover where I had been at fault seemed to be such an arduous and dangerous task. It was painful to pause and look backward. I was afraid I might stumble! Couldn’t I put the past out of my mind and just live in my new golden present? I realized that those in the past whom I had harmed stood between me and my desire to continue my movement toward serenity. I had to ask for courage to face those persons from my life who still lived in my conscience, to recognize and deal with the guilt that their presence produced in me. I had to look at the damage I had done, and become willing to make amends. Only then could my journey of the spirit resume.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 22:49:02 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 240811</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240811.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240811.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>REMOVING “THE GROUND GLASS”</p></h1>
<p><em>The moral inventory is a cool examination of the damages that occurred to us during life and a sincere effort to look at them in a true perspective. This has the effect of taking the ground glass out of us, the emotional substance that still cuts and inhibits.</em>
<br/></p>
<p class='right'>AS BILL SEES IT, p. 140</p>
<p><br><br>
My Eighth Step list used to drag me into a whirlpool of resentment. After four years of sobriety, I was blocked by denial connected with an ongoing abusive relationship. The argument between fear and pride eased as the words of the Step moved from my head to my heart. For the first time in years I opened my box of paints and poured out an honest rage, an explosion of reds and blacks and yellows. As I looked at the drawing, tears of joy and relief flowed down my cheeks.  In my disease, I had given up my art, a self-inflicted punishment far greater than any imposed from outside. In my recovery, I learned that the pain of my defects is the very substance God uses to cleanse my character and to set me free.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 22:50:03 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 240810</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240810.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240810.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>REDOUBLING OUR EFFORTS</p></h1>
<p><em>To a degree, he has already done this when taking moral inventory, but now the time has come when he ought to redouble his efforts to see how many people he had hurt, and in what ways.</em>
<br/></p>
<p class='right'>-TWELVE STEPS AND TWELVE TRADITIONS , p. 77</p>
<p><br><br>
REDOUBLING OUR EFFORTS</p>
<p>As I continue to grow in sobriety, I become more aware of myself as a person of worth. In the process, I am better able to see others as persons, and with this comes the realization that these were people whom I had hurt in my drinking days. I didn’t just lie, I lied about Tom. I didn’t just cheat, I cheated Joe. What were seemingly impersonal acts, were really personal affronts, because it was people – people of worth – whom I had harmed. I need to do something about the people I have hurt so that I may enjoy a peaceful sobriety.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 16:59:01 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 240809</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240809.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240809.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>“ … OF ALL PERSONS WE HAD HARMED”</p></h1>
<p><em>“ … and became willing to make amends to them all.”</em>
<br/></p>
<p class='right'>TWELVE STEPS AND TWELVE TRADITIONS, p. 77</p>
<p><br><br>
One of the key words in the Eighth Step is the word all. I am not free to select a few names for the list and to disregard others. It is a list of all persons I have harmed. I can see immediately that this Step entails forgiveness because if I’m not willing to forgive someone, there is little chance I will place his name on the list. Before I placed the first name on my list, I said a little prayer: “I forgive anyone and everyone who has ever harmed me at any time and under any circumstances.”  It is well for me to contemplate a small, but very significant, two-letter word every time the Lord’s Prayer is said. The word is as. I ask, “Forgive us our trespasses, as we forgive those who trespass against us.” In this case, as means, “in the same manner.” I am asking to be forgiven in the same manner that I forgive others. As I say this portion of the prayer, if I am harboring hatred or resentment, I am inviting more resentment, when I should be calling on the spirit of forgiveness.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 16:59:01 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 240808</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240808.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240808.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>MADE A LIST … ”</p></h1>
<p><em>Made a list of all persons we had harmed.</em>
<br/></p>
<p class='right'>-TWELVE STEPS AND TWELVE TRADITIONS  p. 77</p>
<p><br><br>
When I approached the Eighth Step, I wondered how I could list all the things that I have done to other people since there were so many people, and some of them weren’t alive anymore. Some of the hurts I inflicted weren’t bad, but they really bothered me. The main thing to see in this Step was to become willing to do whatever I had to do to make these amends to the best of my ability at that particular time. Where there is a will, there’s a way, so if I want to feel better, I need to unload the guilt feeling I have. A peaceful mind has no room for feeling of guilt. With the help of my Higher Power, if I am honest with myself, I can cleanse my mind of these feelings.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 23:06:35 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 240807</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240807.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240807.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>A “DESIGN FOR LIVING”</p></h1>
<p><em>We in our turn, sought the same escape with all the desperation of drowning men. What seemed at first a flimsy reed, has proved to be the loving and powerful hand of God. A new life has been given us or, if you prefer, “a design for living” that really works.</em>
<br/></p>
 <p class='right'>-ALCOHOLIC ANONYMOUS , p. 28</p>
<p><br><br>
I try each day to raise my heart and hands in thanks to God for showing me a “design for living” that really works through our beautiful Fellowship. But what, exactly, is this “design for living” that “really works”? For me, it is the practice of the Twelve Steps to the best of my ability, the continued awareness of a God who loves me unconditionally, and the hope that, in each new day, there is a purpose for my being. I am truly, truly blessed in the Fellowship.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 22:59:02 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 240806</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240806.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240806.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>DRIVEN</p></h1>
<p><em>Driven by a hundred forms of fear, self-delusion, self-seeking and self-pity, we step on the toes of our fellows and they retaliate.</em>
<br/></p>
 <p class='right'>-ALCOHOLIC ANONYMOUS , p. 62</p>
<p><br><br>
My selfishness was the driving force behind my drinking. I drank to celebrate success and I drank to drown my sorrows. Humility is the answer. I learn to turn my will and my life over to the care of God. My sponsor tells me that service keeps me sober. Today I ask myself:  Have I sought knowledge of God’s will for me? Have I done service for my A. A. group?</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 240805</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240805.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240805.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>LISTENING DEEPLY, p.226</p></h1>
<p><em>How persistently we claim the right to decide all by ourselves just what we shall think and just how we shall act.</em>
<br/></p>
 <p class='right'>-TWELVE STEPS AND TWELVE TRADITIONS, p. 37</p>
<p><br><br>
If I accept and act upon the advice of those who have made the program work for themselves, I have a chance to outgrow the limits of the past. Some problems will shrink to nothingness, while others may require patient, well-thought-out action. Listening deeply when others share can develop intuition in handling problems which arise unexpectedly. It is usually best for me to avoid impetuous action.  Attending a meeting or calling a fellow A.A. member will usually reduce tension enough to bring relief to a desperate sufferer like me. Sharing problems at meetings with other alcoholics to whom I can relate, or privately with my sponsor, can change aspects of the positions in which I find myself. Character defects are identified and I begin to see how they work against me. When I put my faith in the spiritual power of the program, when I trust others to teach me what I need to do to have a better life, I find that I can trust myself to do what is necessary.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 EST</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>daily reflections / 240804</title>
<link>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240804.html</link>
<guid>https://williamthazard.github.io/daily-reflections/days/240804.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[
<h1><p class='center'>SEEDS OF FAITH</p></h1>
<p><em>Faith, to be sure, is necessary, but faith alone can avail nothing. We can have faith, yet keep God out of our lives.</em>
<br/></p>
 <p class='right'>-TWELVE STEPS AND TWELVE TRADITIONS, p. 34</p>
<p><br><br>
As a child I constantly questioned the existence of God. To a “scientific thinker” like me, no answer could withstand a thorough dissection, until a very patient woman finally said to me, “You must have faith.” With that simple statement, the seeds of my recovery were sown!</p>
<p>Today, as I practice my recovery — cutting back the weeds of alcoholism — slowly I am letting those early seeds of faith to grow and bloom. Each day of recovery, of ardent gardening, brings the Higher Power of my understanding more fully into my life. My God has always been with me through faith, but it is my responsibility to have the willingness to accept His presence. I ask God to grant me the willingness to do His will.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 00:00:00 EST</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
